

# CONTACT

Address: Bilker Allee 140,

40217 Düsseldorf
Phone :+49 1729471513
E-Mail : mano.hicet@gmail.com

# GitHub & LinkedIn

- GitHub URL
- LinkedIn URL
- Portfolio Webpage

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

## Technologies

- Javascript
- HTML5
- CSS3

#### Javascript Frameworks

- React
- jQuery
- Express JS

Web Layout

Bootstrap

Material UI

Node JS

#### Databases

- MongoDB
- MYSQL
- Oracle
- SQL Server

#### Version Control

# • Git

#### **Programming**

- C
- C++
- Visual Basic
- Power Builder

#### LANGUAGES

- Tamil (Mother Tongue)
- English : Fluent (C1)Deutsch : Intermediate

#### **PASSIONS**

- Yoga & Meditation
- Mandala Drawing
- Cooking

# MANONMANI SELVAKUMAR

# FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

#### **ABOUT**

Full Stack Web Developer with hands-on Experience in Teaching Computer Science Technologies who is about to graduate a 1-year Intensive Training in MERN Stack. Seeking an Internship Position to apply the collected earlier experience and Web Technologies to challenge myself and deliver solution-oriented approaches.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Course| Digital Career Institute | Since Jul 2020 | Düsseldorf

During the Course of study, deeply exploring technologies of MERN stack by learning and applying them to various practical projects.

Working on Designing the Front End for the final project using Material UI and JavaScript frameworks.

Accomplished Deutsch Course with Intermediate Level C1 during the Period May 2018 till Feb 2020.

Time off for the Personal & Professional Development and focusing on Family to actively grow and integrate in the Intercultural Environment from mid 2010 till 2018.

Master of Philosophy (Computer Science) | Bharathiar University, India | 2005-2006 Master of Computer Applications | Bharathiar University, India | 1999-2002

Bachelors in Computer Science | Bharathiar University, India | 1996-1999

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

PROFESSOR

Swami Vivekananda PG College | Jun 2009 - May 2010 | India

Conducted Postgraduate Lectures on Various areas of Computer Science and did Researching on New Subject topic areas to teach.

Hindusthan College of Engineering & Technology| Jun 2008 - May 2009 | India Challenged and Motivated Students through in-depth lectures and discussions on WebTecnology, Computer Networks and Database Concepts.

PSG College of Arts & Science | Jan 2003 - Nov 2006 | India

Taught Introductory and Upper Level Courses in Computer Science and Applications.

Motivated and encouraged the Students to do better and achieve more by conducting Quiz and printing Monthly Magazine.

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

Tamilnadu Infotech (P) Ltd| Jan 2003 - Nov 2006 | India

Developed a School Automation Desktop Application using PowerBuilder and SQL Server

### **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

- Lavilla : <a href="https://manonmani-s.github.io/la\_villa/">https://manonmani-s.github.io/la\_villa/</a>
  - Using HTML and CSS designed a Responsive Web Page for Interiors and Luxury Fabrics Collections.
- JWT Authentication
  - Created a React application for securely transmitting information between parties as a JSON object.
- Bootstrap Theme: https://manonmani-.github.io/bootstrap\_exercise\_kindness/#